♪ In the not to distant future ♪
♪ We're down in Deep 13 ♪
♪ Doctor Forrester
and TV's Frank ♪
♪ Were hatching an evil scheme ♪
♪ They hired a temp
by the name of Mike ♪
♪ Just a regular Joe
the didn't like ♪
♪ Their experiment
needed a good test case ♪
♪ So they cocked
him on the nugget ♪
♪ And they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll settle in
cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ You'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And they wanna
enter his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in Mike
can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ We've tried to
keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot, Gypsy,
Tom Servo, Crow ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ Go Mystery Science
Theater 3,000 ♪
- And so you see
Mike because of that
you could never be a
truly world-class dancer.
- Hey, I guess.
Hi everyone, welcome to
the satellite of love,
I'm Mike and these are my bots.
Servo is just.
(smoke alarm wailing)
- Okay, people.
This is a fire drill.
Listen up, Crow, you
grab the photo album,
Mike, you dial 911.
- Roger.
- Tom, you get the flashlight.
- But this doesn't
make any sense
if there were an actual.
- Now stand in a straight line
and proceed in an orderly manner
and no talking.
Let's go.
(fire alarm wailing)
- There really is
no place to go.
- Well, still we
gotta meet code.
- No talking in line.
- We'll be right back.
(upbeat music)
You guys look ridiculous.
- Jealous.
- I am mot.
- Are too.
- I am not.
Let me just try it on though.
- No.
- I probably look pretty.
- Come on, let me just.
I'll just wear it for a second.
- Guys, I think that's
a crazy cat calling.
- Put a sock in it Reddit dare.
Kids, I'd like to demonstrate
how business and science
walk hand in sweaty hand.
Hypothesis.
Anything can be sold to anyone
via my new process of
pinpoint marketing.
Frank!
Normal marketing campaigns
allow some people
to slip through the
gill nets of commerce,
whereas my pinpoint
marketing sits on
the customers chest and
dangles loogies in his face
until he buys.
Don't mind me
mixing my metaphors.
Frank!
My product?
Anything will do, say
cigarettes, Frank!
Give them the hard sell, Frank.
- Nelson cigarettes for the
spirit of Nelson in all of us.
- Work it now,
Frank's, sizzle it.
- Nelson cigarettes for the
spirit of Nelson in all of us.
- As my assistant sends you
your new favorite cigarettes
via the Umbilicon,
prepare to witness
pin point marketing.
- I know, but it doesn't matter.
- Okay, here it is.
- Wow, cool.
- Let me look at that.
Mike it's you and you're cool.
- But I don't smoke.
- Well, isn't it
time you started.
- No, it's bad for you
- Fine, smoking is bad
and there's no other side to it,
that's real open mind, Mike.
- Look at this,
Nelson cigarettes
for the rugged individual
trapped in space.
- Come on Mike, live a little.
Smoking is a great way to
assert your independence.
- Look, pin point
marketing or not,
I don't like smoking
and I'm not gonna start.
- You know, you're
not man enough
to smoke Nelson, Nelson.
- Fine, have it your way.
You could have been so Nelson,
you disgust me.
Well, your movie this week
is a little butt of a film,
called "The Dead Talk Back".
- Howdy.
- Morning, may I?
Well Nelson, your
first short film
is a little product
called the selling wizard
and I hope you get freezer burn.
- Mike, you can get a
free Nelson waterbed
for just 20,000
proof of purchase.
We got movies all lined up.
- An high-octane surge.
Hi, my name's Merlin
and I would love
to see you in this Camaro.
- They'll bring in
a material world.
- [Narrator] You, the
ice cream manufacturer.
- Up against the
wall, spread 'em.
- [Narrator] You, the
frozen food distributor.
- Ben and Jerry
before Woodstock.
- And you, the food retailer.
- These three people
will square off.
- [Narrator] Stand
the day in the midst
of a selling revolution.
- The selling revolution
will not be televised.
- [Narrator] You're
in a merchandising era
of self-service.
- So, dig in.
- [Narrator] Where
display and accessibility
are the key to
successful merchandising.
- Man, that looks good.
- [Narrator] Today's
problem is merchandising.
- Over three kinds of vanilla.
- [Narrator] To sell in
high volume for high profit.
- For high people.
- [Narrator] Products
are impulse items.
- I'll take it, I'll take it.
- [Narrator] And impulse
buying is primarily.
- Women's fault.
- [Narrator] An
emotional decision.
- The market crashed.
- [Narrator] Understanding this,
manufacturers spend
millions on package design.
- This is the result.
- [Narrator] But despite
an appealing package
or quality of the product,
it's not enough.
- Man, I hate this job.
- [Narrator] You
can't sell in volume
if the frozen product
isn't easily identified,
attractively displayed
and within buying reach.
- Don't tell me what I can't do,
who is this guy?
- [Narrator] What it takes
to effectively merchandise
frozen products today
is an automatic salesman,
a real selling wizard.
- Like me.
- [Narrator] Yes, the successful
automatic salesman has.
- Left the building.
- [Narrator] What?
Who are you?
- Forget the ice cream,
I'll be right back.
- [Narrator] A selling wizard?
Well, you have sales appeal
and capacity, I'll say that.
- But lose the outfit.
- [Narrator] But actually,
right now we're interested in.
What's that?
You know the answers
to merchandising frozen
products successfully?
Fine, let's go.
- Are you married?
- [Narrator] Yes,
this is the answer.
A real selling wizard.
- Are we in heaven?
- Rip off.
- [Narrator] All new
glass-front cabinets,
a silent salesman that
offers greater profits to you
with sales appeal styling,
space-saving capacity,
new product developments.
- It's a little big,
I just want a hot plate.
- [Narrator] And what's
the first feature
that makes the selling wizard.
- Bosoms.
- [Narrator] Sales
appeal styling.
- Or SAS.
- [Narrator] And this cabinet
offers sales appeal in action.
Hear your customers instantly,
see all the I and by
appeal of your product
through this maximum
glass area front.
- Look at them gather around.
- [Narrator] Around
the narrow rail
and through the wider
sales design top opening.
- To grandmother's house we go.
- [Narrator] No barrier
between food and customer.
An open invitation to buy.
- I dare you not to buy this.
- [Narrator] Still another
advantage of this easy eye view,
you can inventory your stock
in a matter of seconds.
One glance and you know
if the cabinet requires filling.
- Just one glance,
don't look back.
- [Narrator] In addition,
this cabinet automatically
bills plus profits for you.
- This is frozen cotton?
- [Narrator] Surveys
show that sales
of high profit impulse
items such as ice cream.
- Or smack.
- [Narrator] Score
consistently higher turnover,
averaging 53% greater sales
without any special
price inducements or
selling campaigns.
- First ones free.
- [Narrator] When cabinets were
kept orderly and kept full.
- That's when men were men.
- [Narrator] Then
picture for yourself
the sales turnover possibilities
with this easy to see,
easy to reach display
working for you.
- I'll take it, I'll
take it, I wanna.
Gimme, gimme gimme.
- [Narrator] And notice
how these convenient,
horizontal wire shelves
put your product always
within buying range.
- Give it to me, gimme.
- [Narrator] They may
be removed entirely
for loading to full
cabinet capacity.
- But don't put
your tongue on it.
- [Narrator] And this
extra storage space,
means you can offer
wider variety,
cut rush period shortages,
reduce deliveries.
- And if you're into that?
- [Narrator] And this stainless
steel shelf superstructure,
an integral part of the cabinet,
gives you valuable
tie in display space.
- Barbecue sauce?
- [Narrator] Yet
allows a clear view
of adjoining aisle displays.
- Snouts and knuckles.
- [Narrator] Or if it's a
deluxe superstructure you want.
- She's got a big
scab on her knees.
- [Narrator] Gentlemen
if you please.
- You filthy degenerates.
- [Narrator] Thank you.
- No, thank you.
- [Narrator] This
attention-getting superstructure
with its eye appeal display
is designed to fit over
the stainless steel
shelf type cabinet top.
- You can't look away, can you?
- [Narrator] The
pictures may be removed
if more shelf
space is necessary,
to boost the sale of
high profit tie-in items.
- Where do I sign,
I want it now,
name your price.
- [Narrator] And speaking
of attention getters,
notice this direct
fluorescent lighting.
Light just inches
above the package level
to give your merchandise
real floodlight attention.
- Turn on your floodlights.
- [Narrator] With this cabinet
every frozen product
is easily identified,
effectively displayed,
right at your
customer's fingertips.
Yes, on every count.
- Guilty.
- [Narrator] Anheuser-Busch
automatic salesman scores high
on sales appeal styling.
- Next step, open
a grocery store.
- [Narrator] And here's the
next outstanding feature;
real space-saving capacity.
- She seems almost lifelike.
- [Narrator] 14
cubic feet capacity,
17 cubic feet capacity.
- A million cubic feet capacity.
- [Narrator] Three glass-front
merchandising cabinets
to fit your individual needs.
- What if I need love?
- [Narrator] Every
one of these models
is built to give you
maximum cubic capacity
for each foot of
store floor space.
- This freezer rules.
- [Narrator] Here's
top level loading,
just inches from the top.
- Hey, let's see
some bottom loading.
- [Narrator] And here's
the new combination
of storage and sales space,
which means that foot for
foot of length and width.
Anheuser-Busch offers
more cubic foot capacity.
- Than all of mankind.
- [Narrator] And the kind of
design that fits naturally,
yet adds to the quality
appearance of any store.
- And it's a hide-a-bed.
- [Narrator] Speaking of beauty,
what's our next?
Product development.
- Starts at age 12.
- [Narrator]
Anheuser-Busch pioneered
in the refrigeration field
to solve their own refrigeration
in merchandising problems.
- With a typewriter?
- This refrigeration experience
was combined with years
of merchandising know how
to offer you three all-new
glass front models.
- I wanna see more freezers.
- [Narrator] And now,
here is a fourth.
- Daddy, can I have it.
Please, oh please, oh please.
- [Narrator] A cabinet with
the same sales appeal styling
and space-saving capacity,
plus the newest refrigeration
method yet developed.
- Coldness.
- [Narrator] Forced
air refrigeration
with the automatic defrost.
- So the one I bought
didn't have that,
what is this?
- [Narrator] And now wizard,
can we see how forced air
automatic defrost makes this
the most advanced open top
automatic salesman ever made.
- Are they allowed to show that?
- [Narrator] This
simplified sketch,
showing a cross-section
of the cabinet.
- Makes no sense.
- [Narrator] Illustrates
how the return air
is drawn through a
series of four passages,
where cooled fins cool the air
to 35 degrees or 40
degrees below zero.
- Better plugging the car.
- [Narrator] This blower,
then moves the sub-zero air,
up the rear wall of the
cabinet to the deflector,
from which it passes across
the top of the frozen product
and repeats the cycle.
- And it comes out here.
- [Narrator] All
merchandise in the cabinet
is wrapped in a layer
of super cold air.
And this forced air
refrigeration offers unlimited.
- Where's my ice cream?
- [Narrator] Regardless
of package size.
You can move or remove
the partitions entirely.
- Look, it's up to you.
I can't make all your decision.
- [Narrator] And
here's the time control
of the automatic defrost.
Once the timer is set, you
always offer merchandise
at its frost free best.
The sketch shows how the
defrosting is accomplished
by the defroster blower
and the electric
heater elements.
When the timer calls
for defrosting,
this blower and these
heaters go to work at once.
- Singing gaily.
- [Narrator] Warm air is
recirculated over the fins,
melting the frost in
a matter of minutes.
And while the unit is
defrosting swiftly, positively,
the frozen products
in the cabinet
are completely protected,
as warm air is contained
and recirculated
within the cooling compartment.
And the melted frost runs down
into a bladder like pan.
Automatically resumes the
forced air refrigeration cycle.
- This balance of power
keeps ice cream in check.
- [Narrator] And here's
another new feature
on all four glass front models.
This solid non scuff anodized
aluminum panels creates
the attractive all-metal
front appearance,
assurance of lasting beauty.
In addition, the front panel
serves as a convenient,
easy to use night cover.
- To make hot love on.
- [Narrator] Built-in feature.
A stainless steel bumper guard
for greater protection
of your cabinet.
Yes, the development
of these features
is the result of
refrigeration experience,
combined with personal
merchandising knowledge.
- Well, not too personal.
- [Narrator] Every
cabinet designed with
your needs in mind.
- But I need a stove.
- The pizza dominatrix.
- [Narrator] You wanna show us
the complete line of cabinets.
A model to fit every
retailer's individual need.
- That was close, she was mad.
- [Narrator] If it's
storage you need,
here's the first of
eight models available,
ranging from three to 12
to 22 cubic foot capacity.
- That's mine, that's more me.
- [Narrator] And
this all-purpose,
two-lid utility storage cabinet
with 23 cubic foot capacity.
- Bodies stack easily.
- [Narrator] Accommodates
92 1/2 gallons
in 2 1/2 gallon cans,
stacked three high
or 930 Philadelphia pints.
- Or a million
thimble sizes pints.
- [Narrator] And for those
who want 100% selling
and storage capacity.
- Get over it.
- [Narrator] This is one
of seven remote models
that provides a range of seven
to 22 cubic foot capacity.
- How am I ever gonna decide?
- [Narrator] And this open
top model is one of two,
built to give best
possible merchandising
with an open top
non glass model.
- I'm not gonna show
you the other one.
- [Narrator] This is one of two
sliding glass top
models available
with glass sealed tops
cushioned by rubber
in a stainless steel frame,
to move at fingertip pressure.
Here's the island merchandiser,
designed for promotion specials
and heavy store traffic lanes.
- It doubles as a tollbooth.
- [Narrator] Accesibblefrom
all four sides,
it's mounted on rollers
for easy movement
to busy store locations.
- This changes everything,
now I want this one.
- [Narrator] Once again,
outstanding features
that Anheuser-Busch make
for a real selling wizard.
- You know, I think
I'll just buy a thermos.
- [Narrator] Sales appeal style.
The kind of design
that beckons customer
to see and reach
for frozen products.
- Plenty of lip
and tongue action.
- [Narrator] Space
saving capacity
that gives maximum storage
and selling use of
every inch of space.
- Meanwhile the soviets
were launching Sputnik.
- [Narrator] And constant
product development.
Forced-air automatic defrost,
many other features,
all adding up to greater profits
for you the ice
cream manufacturer,
the frozen food distributor,
the food retailer.
- The guy with a bad coat.
- [Narrator] Because
this automatic salesman,
a real selling wizard,
means increased volume,
greater profits.
- She likes me.
- [Narrator] Trough
better merchandising
with Anheuser-Busch,
manufacturers of quality
refrigeration equipment.
- And remember to buy Ed
McMahon's Budweiser ice cream.
- Leni Riefenstahl's
most powerful film.
(upbeat music)
- Isn't this a Mahler symphony.
- This is where all the
Farnese gutters starts.
- Certain actors
own their roles,
Farnese's is Mr. Krasker,
simply brilliant.
- Tonight's episode,
"The Dead Go Fishing"
with special guest
star Robert Culp.
- This is the heyday
the Bongo Players union,
top Billing in all
major motion pictures.
- Appreciation to Lewin
and nice community center.
- Ironically, he's dead now.
- Hey, Tom Poston on the mix.
- Hey, you got your
tongue in my mouth.
mouth in my tongue.
- You always know the best
places to take people.
- It's two in the morning,
I gotta get a better
stalking schedule.
- Look, we're
married for 25 years,
at least let me
get to second base.
- Alice and Sam the
butcher on a date.
- Great, I suppose I'll
have to clean that up.
- Well, pal.
If you're gonna
murdered somebody,
cease the moments.
- Nope, nope.
That didn't do it either.
Sorry, nothing.
- It was a bitter affair
that ended briefly.
Mike Wallace, "Night-Beat".
- Well, that
interview went well.
It must have been Arbor Day.
- Excuse me, any of you know
what evil lurks in
the heart of man.
- I just had to step outside
for a fresh of breath air.
- Good night Mrs.
Calabash, wherever you are.
- The first movie filmed
entirely with flashlights.
- Come on Mauro, I only
got two more D-cells left.
- Ellie blew their budget
on those Bongo players.
I just said a lot of B's.
- With 34 cylinders,
the cars of yesteryear
were impossible to flood.
- She's flooding the radio.
- And creepy Triple-A is there.
- Maybe this isn't my car.
- He's not since
Moonraker's events,
it's an exciting
opening sequence.
- Stalking's hard when
you don't have a car.
- Dumb stupid, I'm gonna
go back in the car.
- James Farentino,
this is Tina Sinatra.
- Here's the proper
way to start a car.
- [Narrator] The motion
picture you are about to see
is based on a true incident,
taken from a recent
psychic research file.
- Wait a minute, can
we go back a bit,
I'm a little confused.
- He's gonna tell us about
trade school, isn't he?
- Hard time for
Maximilian Schell.
- Yes, may I help you?
- Have you been hearing
some weird stories recently?
- About Chuck Berry.
- About telepathy?
- I knew you were
gonna say that.
- The fourth dimension?
- Or Marilyn McCoo.
- Or ghosts?
- No, it doesn't ring a bell,
we must have the wrong movie.
- The case that I'm working
on on the present time
involves a little of each.
- Hang on a sec here,
I just got this one thing.
- Me.
- You.
- Who am I?
- Frankly, I've forgotten.
- I'm a private investigator,
criminology is my hobby.
- I sell parts of
my record collection
to make ends meet,
I also manage a bowling alley.
Look, I'm kind of between
projects at the moment.
Mike help me.
- My philosophy.
- Arts of leather.
- Metaphysics.
What is metaphysics?
- It's really hard.
- There's a long complicated
explanation to that question.
- Which he'll be
happy to give us.
- But to make it simple,
a meta physician doesn't believe
you're dead when you die.
- So, he's not much help
at an accident scene.
- What am i working on now?
- I got a development
deal at FOX.
- Interesting project.
A radio.
- He's got a he's kit.
- To communicate
with the departed.
A device that mechanically
speak to the dead.
It's true, it can't be done.
- My mom said so.
- It's just a matter of finding
the right frequency
or vibration.
- Who am I?
I covered that.
- Wouldn't it be fantastic
to be able to speak to someone
who has just passed over?
- Quit squirming.
- I just think, we could
find lost articles,
treasures, gold mines.
- You're not buying
any of this, are you?
- We could even solve murders
by just contacting the murdered.
- I'm so lonely.
- By going directly to
the source, so to speak.
- And passing the
savings on to you.
- Here, I'll give
you a demonstration.
- Let's kill somebody.
- This.
- Is this.
- There's something like
the first crystal sets.
- Well, in a really vague way.
- Never could perfect
electronic too powerful enough
to reach the high
vibrations necessary.
- To be in The Cramps.
- Leon, what are you
doing down there?
- Mom, I'm talking to the dead.
- Did you look for a job today?
- I put in some applications.
- But?
- Nothing.
- It takes a while for
temperature attunement,
there we go.
We'll try it again later.
- Are you wearing corduroy,
because that affects
the radio, you know.
You should also
wash your hair a lot
so the vibrations work.
- That's gonna take a
while, you wanna hang out?
We could play air hockey,
but we have to be kind of quiet
coz my dad works third shift.
- The problem not communicating
with the departed.
- Is that they're dead.
- Goes way back.
- Way back to the
early days of stuff.
- I'm sorry, I
failed to tell you.
- I'm made of liverwurst.
- Here, I want to
show you something.
- This is Laura, my secretary.
- Here's an interesting gadget.
- My winky, sorry.
(horn blaring)
- Stop that.
It's hard for him to
make friends I think.
- Perchance someone
is buried alive,
this makes sure the outside
world knows about it.
- Admittedly, I haven't sold
many yet but I'm hoping.
- So even when you're
dead you can annoy people.
- Radio's still warming up,
we'll get back to
that in a minute.
- The case that I'm working
on now started a few days ago
at the rooming
house, where I live.
- Will Rogers was staying over.
- [Narrator] The names of
individuals in the location
are the only deviations made.
- At a beaver's house
all of a sudden.
- [Narrator] To the exact events
that led up to the
time of the murder.
- Realize this is under protest,
you just can't talk to the dead.
- I can't talk to the dead.
- Mike is there no place
for mystery or wonder
in that stringy heart of yours.
- No.
- Well, then get ready
as we simultaneously grind
your mealy face in our triumph
and pulling huge
Arbitron ratings too.
- Fine, you're on the air.
- Hello and welcome to
"The Dead Talk Back",
the show that gives you
the ultimate last word.
- We're taking calls
from anyone who's dead,
give us a call,
let us know what's on
your mind as it were.
- You're dead, the show
is "The Dead Talk Back",
give us a call,
you know the number
'coz you're dead.
- They're not gonna call.
- Hey, there's our first call.
Hello, you're on the air.
- [Man] This is Abe from
Illinois and I would love.
- Abe, you wouldn't
by any chance be the?
- Yes, the great
emancipator, right?
Listen, what I wanted to know.
- Abrahan Lincoln.
Mr. Lincoln this
is such an honor.
I've always wanted to ask
you about the dark days
during the Civil War.
- Sure, whatever.
Look, what I'm wondering
is if you guys think
the bills are going back the
Big Dance again this year
and I'll just hang
up and listen.
- Mr. Lincoln, no the.
- That's the old
Railsplitter wondering
if the Buffalo Bills will
be returning this Superbowl.
- Will they fall
in five straight.
- That was Abraham
Lincoln, don't you?
- Okay, we got
another call here.
- You're on the air.
- This is Mr.
Churchill from England.
- Winston Churchill.
Mr. Churchill, listen
the Iron Curtain is down.
Now, do you have any
thoughts on where our nation?
- The Bills don't
have the cojones
to make it to another ballgame.
Jim Kelly is a fine
quarterback and a great Patriot
but he will never ever
wear a Super Bowl ring,
good day.
- How do you know.
- Unbelievable.
- I know, where does
that guy get off saying
the Bills won't make it back.
- If they sign Thurman
Thomas in the defensive line.
- In case anybody
drives up and asks,
that was Winston Churchill.
(upbeat music)
- A sure thing Danny.
- After you sin
filled those minutes,
you will go to damnation as
sure as I'm sitting here.
- Quiet, will you.
- Pass the Dutch loaf.
- If you'd live a little
more of what you preach
it'd be a lot
easier to live with.
- [Narrator] Meet the
rest of the people
that contribute to
this strange case.
Mrs. Coleman, the landlady.
A widow for the last 12 years.
- She can really pack it away.
- [Narrator] Fritz Kruger,
one thing on his mind.
- Reunification.
- So help me Kruger,
if you don't take your
blasted eyes off me
I'll throw something at you.
- I didn't think it
was that obvious.
- [Narrator] Renee Caldwell,
models for a living.
- Models freezers.
- [Narrator] In an hour
and a half she'll be dead.
My name is Henry Creswell,
I've been living here
for the past two years.
It's convenient
to my laboratory.
Sarah Sthoil's sons,
Dennis and Ronnie,
husband just
disappeared one day.
- There he is.
- [Narrator] Arnold Younger,
strange and very quiet,
keeps to himself.
He works as a clerk
in a music shop,
and boarding here for a year.
Raymond Milburn, from
a wealthy family,
refined fine young man
likes music and the arts.
He separated from his family,
he's trying his luck
as a radio announcer.
- Not going that well.
- Hope Byington, going to
be married next spring,
she's a close friend of Rene's.
Occupation, cashier.
- Telling them innocent
kids stories about the dead
and their haunting's,
that's the work of the devil.
You'll pay for it.
The devil.
- That's where I know you from.
- That man is it devil himself.
- Shut up you potentate
of righteousness.
- Listen to him,
he'll pay to God
for his sinful talk.
- You gonna finish that?
- Man is superior to
all the living kingdom,
he has nothing
else to do on earth
but to be ready for the
new coming of the Lord.
- Hallelujah.
- Ronnie!
- [Narrator] Christy Mattling,
close to Bible well.
I can't say the
same about his work,
he does so little of it.
A friendless sort of a man.
- As I rather like him.
- That does it.
That explained there's
no work policy.
- Fine, fine, everyone
pick on the devil.
- I've gotta go meet
with Richard Avedon,
madly merchants.
- [Narrator] Each word that
was set prior to the incident
was carefully reconstructed
in the search.
Every movement of the victim
was verified as accurate.
- To make these
lovely figurines.
- Mr. Krasker, I don't
know why you put up
with that holy personality.
- He's not really that bad,
at least he keeps
nothing to himself.
What he has to says, he says.
- I think he likes me.
- He doesn't worry
me as much as Kruger.
I know it's none of my business
but if he ever tries
getting funny just call out.
- And I'll get some help.
- Well, so far all he's
ever done is just luck.
- Say, you wouldn't
be interested in a
radio that could.
- She wants me pretty much.
- What's the complete
history of transistors,
I'm in for the evening.
- Just one last look
at that corridor.
- It's my halter-top,
he's hogging the bathroom.
- Looks like Maggie the cat.
- It's not petted out, okay?
- Pete Townsend.
- Staying in again tonight.
- I'm staying in tonight
but I don't like it.
I'm bored silly.
- What's the matter
with you lately, Renee?
For the last couple of months.
- Don't you start on me now.
- it's not all glamor being
a Fleet Farm underwear
model you know.
- So round, so firm,
so fully packed.
- I'm sorry.
It's just that I've had
a lot on my mind lately.
I have an appointment tomorrow
with the Soul Tuppence agency.
If it works out, it'll mean
a week's work on the yacht,
but taking a whole
crew down to Catalina:
models, electrician,
photographers.
- Pipe fitters.
- It's for a national mag,
but with my luck.
- [Narrator] From Renee
Caldwell's strange behavior,
we assume that she was in
some sort of serious trouble
and in no mood to
discuss her worries
with her friend of many years.
- Or that weird girl
who just left her room.
- Look, "My Father the
Hero", is out in video now.
- I hate you society.
- Well, I'll think I'll pluck
my forehead skin some more.
- I know, I'll smoke face
down on my polyester sheets.
- Maybe I should take
a shower before I die.
- NC-17, 50s style.
- [Narrator] The time
was now 8:45 p.m.
She had 45 minutes more to live.
We thought that she spent
the last moments in her room
and that she saw no
one during that time.
We were later proved wrong.
- Why'd you bring it up?
- [Narrator] Her
background was similar
to thousands of girls
that have come to this
large western city,
finding suitable work
and friends and quarters;
these things were
a problem at first.
Her father died
when she was seven,
and her mother worked to support
her and her three sisters.
When she became of age,
she managed to exist modestly
on her earnings as a model.
- Real modesty.
- But her restless
nature demanded more
than just existing.
A violent death was
to be her destiny.
I'm a police lieutenant
in charge of reconstruction
of the evening's events
and finding her murderer.
- I probably should have
told you that earlier,
I admit it, I had
something to do with it.
- Well, I gotta go
get killed, I'm late.
Death waits for no one.
- Renee now had 39.5
minutes to live,
she now at 39 minutes to live,
she now had 38.75
minutes to live,
she now at 38 minutes to live.
Renee now had, let's see,
somewhere between 35 and
37 minutes left to live.
Adjusting her windage.
- I'm gonna tell Kruger
to stop thinking about me.
Hey, hand me out
my Chevy's please.
- I gotta talk to you,
it's very important.
- I think I'm a chicken.
- I don't have the time Renee,
I'll be late for work.
- You better find the time.
- After this film,
T-shirt sales skyrocketed.
- Hey, I didn't
think you could get
a sheet metal
press in this room,
is meal ever over for you?
- All the kids in bed Sarah?
- Ronnie has finally
got him to sleep,
Danny went to a scout meeting.
- That is so interesting.
- Ma, why do you put up
with that religious
fanatic anyway?
- He's harmless.
He sparks a lot of
noise about religion
but he pays his rent.
- [Narrator] The time, 9:05 p.m.
All occupants of the
house were accounted for.
The landlady and her daughter
who was sitting
just 30 feet away
from where the murder was to
take place 25 minutes from now.
- You know the murder
is not gonna be
that suspenseful
when it happens.
- Now, that was okay.
- Good, this room
is even more dreary.
- Dial M for Monday.
- I woke up I wasn't
there, you hate that.
- Well let's see,
14 minutes to live,
wonder if I can get
a pizza in that time.
- Hi, I know I'm not
supposed to call you there.
- You being Amish and all.
- Look, I can't stay in this
house night after night.
- I'm a nocturnal model.
- Good, I'll meet
you in 20 minutes.
- I think I better
get some light bulbs.
(upbeat music)
- It's your hero.
- Forget it, she's long gone.
- From Maidenform woman,
you'll never know where
she'll be murdered.
- Where are my water wings?
- She's sneaking into
her own lingerie drawer.
- This is Harry Connick
Seniors girlfriend.
- [Narrator] The time, 9 18 p.m.
12 minutes of life left.
Does a person get a premonition
that they're going to die?
Is there a signal or warning?
- Just a voice.
- [Narrator] If there was any
indication of impending death,
Renee Caldwell apparently
was not aware of it.
- How could she be so stupid?
- Renee decided to go
over to Mount Pilot.
- Damn, I'm gonna
miss the commish.
- Renee, do you have
change for a 10?
- The eyes of Kenneth Mars.
- My mom says I'm grounded,
I can't come over.
- Rene, you're not
supposed to be watering,
there's a sprinkling ban,
thought you should know.
- Shoot that poison
arrow through my heart.
- Well, murder by implication.
What good shot model will
often hide in the woods
up to three hours?
- Make sure no one
finds that he wraps it
in Bob Herbert's column.
- [Narrator] A fiendish
murder had taken place,
but yards away.
- The binging continued.
- [Narrator] Silently taken
for no visible reason.
At 9:30 p.m. Renee
Caldwell was dead.
- Now, on to my next case.
- It's getting late,
Danny must be coming home.
- You're not gonna
not eat, are you?
- And don't slam
that door young lady.
- Tag, you're it, no tag backs.
- Wait for it, get ready,
look it up and down, now.
- That's my bolero jacket.
(police siren wailing)
- And the police immediately
stroll to the scene.
- You look at that,
all the books Joyce Carol
Oates published last month.
- Lieutenant.
- Kiss me hard.
- The coroner says
there's not much doubt
about the cause of death,
but he'll send us
a complete report
as soon as he
finishes the autopsy.
- Harry, I want a complete
background investigation
on that girl, search
the entire block
and see what you
can come up with,
and keep those reporters
off the grounds
until the lab is finished.
Miss Byington, pull
yourself together.
I know it's difficult, but
I must ask these questions.
Time is very important to
us, every moment counts.
- Sorry lieutenant, I guess
you men see this everyday.
- Actually it has been a while
since the last crossbow murder.
- Don't you believe it?
I don't think I'll ever
get careless to murder.
- Now where's the stiff.
- Crazy, it just
couldn't have happened.
Who'd want to?
- Who has the time?
- There's no reason.
- Harry, you get a list for
friends and acquaintances.
Try to go back as
far as you can.
Mrs. Stoihl, can't you
tell us anything more?
Positively, about what
the man looked like.
You said he was shorter than I.
- And I resent that.
- Would you say that he
weighed about the same as I do?
- It was hard to tell,
he had on a big coat.
- And no pants that
I can remember.
- It was dark outside and
his hat was pulled down.
- Does that sound right?
- I didn't give it much
thought at the time.
- The crossbow seemed
perfectly natural.
- I did see him
trip as he ran away.
- Do I get a meal?
- That would account for
the heel, lieutenant,
it's on its way to the lab.
- A heel?
- Yes, they found a heel wedged
in the step on the front porch.
It looked like it had been torn
recently from a man's shoe.
Now, do you think you could
add anything at all to this?
Did you see the man?
- Not much.
- I ain't kinda dumb.
- I never wanna go through
anything like that again.
- I like Pam.
- The way sh just stood there.
- [Narrator] It
was hard to believe
that no commotion
or noise was heard.
Each of the principals involved
was questioned at the scene.
- That's what makes it so eerie.
I heard nothing.
- Is that a tick on her face?
- Mrs. Stoihl, couldn't
it have been possible
for one of the boys
to have run by you
and come around
back into the house
during the time you
were calling us?
- I guess it would
have been possible.
- I eat biscuits.
- I wanna question each
person in the house,
including the children.
- I don't know what's
what about all that,
they show better
stuff on television.
- And they even let
you see the bites.
- Thanks for that
little commentary
on social mores kids.
It's the Mary Jo
Kopechne Memorial Bridge.
Adolf Hitler is Knight Rider.
- Hey Adolf.
- It just don't work
that well as gloves.
- The heater never
works in this thing,
starts well though.
- One thing about this
getaway, great gas money.
- Zero to 60 in about an hour.
- Hi, I just got off
my shift at Perkins.
- I just heard Louis.
- Hello, Henry, this struck
close to home, didn't it?
Sorry to take you away
from your laboratory
but we need all the
help we can get.
- You know anybody?
- I hear you're working on
some interesting projects.
Why all the secrecy?
- My present projects
aren't secret,
just misunderstood.
- Henry, I've known
you a long time.
- You know, not kneeing
you in the groin
is a constant struggle.
- I don't feel right
about asking but,
you think you can shed any light
on what's happened here tonight?
- Very little.
I left the house
about 1 1/2 hour ago.
- I just finished my ironing.
- My laboratory is within
walking distance from here.
- You've been a great
help to us in the past.
- By staying away.
- Though your methods
weren't always, Orthodox.
- I helped solve eight
cases for you friend, Louis,
with my methods.
- I know.
Where did he find it?
- Behind a garage, found it
buried under some old papers.
- Friar Tuck's been fingered.
- They're good but
we wanted Mac Davis
for our raffle dinner.
I'd ask 'em to leave
but they'd think I was racist.
- Round up all the
usual Bongo players.
- Thank God you're
here officers,
they just came in
and started that.
- Please allow me
to introduce myself,
I'm man who wells and ties.
- And Spooner, Wisconsin
would never be the same.
- Let's go across the street,
see how the Nicholas
brothers are doing.
- Younger, how long you
worked at the music store?
- I've been working for
Mr. Joseph for seven years.
- So your careers
really going places.
- You heard nothing?
- Just bongos.
- I know I heard this
commotion in the hall,
came out to see what it
was and that's all I know.
- How long have you
known Miss. Renee?
What kind of a girl was she?
- In all the time I lived there,
I never even talked to her.
- I did sculp her
in butter once.
- Did you ever take her out?
- Well, I guess maybe I
said hello a few times
when I passed her on the porch.
- Cut the innocent act.
Three things we know about you.
Number one, you were seen
following her home last night.
Number two, you've lent
her small sums of money
from time to time.
- Just $5 one time
and once before $10,
she paid me back.
- Yes, we know.
We found the IOUs in her room,
trusting soul.
And number three, you
were married twice before,
each time they were not
longer than three weeks.
Both divorce papers
contain words
like miserly, mental
torture and fits of anger.
(upbeat music)
- But at Alpine valley,
they did love life,
they did sugar reed,
they took dark stars
into love live,
into sugary.
- Can anyone tell me why
we're dressed like this again?
- Mike, remember the
name of the movie
is the dead talk back,
we're the dead, get it?
- And then the moon came
out and it was jarring,
really big.
♪ Been riding on the
cosmic freak train ♪
♪ And don't you come
around here anymore ♪
(electric guitar music)
(alarm wailing)
- Really nasty.
- Look Phil we've
seen your gear,
let's get on with it.
- Phil seem so taken a
decidedly jar mushi turn.
- Actors we're rolling.
- Hey, that's the thing
that I used to kill.
- In all my years on the force,
I don't think I've ever
seen a more vicious murder.
- God, I love my job.
- Sir, should we be
interrogating him or not?
- Sorry Steve.
- Well, I suppose we probably
ought to get some questions
in here.
- Liz Kruger, what's
you full name?
- Esther, Hoffman, Howard.
- Ivan Ludvig Kruger.
- Arrest him for the accent.
- You look familiar.
- Do you want Star Search?
- A little picture of
a horse I drew sir,
didn't get the tail right.
- You weren't in the house,
so where were you?
- I had a date,
and almost I get to
the girl's house,
I find I don't have a wallet
so I go back.
When I get there I see all
the commotion so I stayed.
- It's mini pearls
murder weapon.
- You ever been arrested?
- Define arrested.
- Yeah.
- You'll betcha.
- Serve any time?
- Two years.
- What was the charge?
- A crossbow killing,
but I had nothing
to do with this one.
- Bothering a girl,
but I don't kill nobody.
- Unless they really deserve it.
- Henry case.
- That's for sure.
- Monkey eyed crowd packer.
- The girl was pretty young,
wasn't she Kruger?
- Kruger, Luger, Booger.
- Well, I guess that's it
for this interrogation.
Meanwhile, at television
city in Hollywood.
(funky jazz music)
- This must be CBS's
replacement for the NFL.
- Excuse us, we're kind of
recording if you don't mind.
- This must be some of
that crazy rock and roll
that the kids are listening to.
- What are you doing?
- It's called the
crossbow sweet hand.
- A child's
introduction to jazz.
- We wanna ask you
some questions.
- Hi, jazz.
- Like I told you before.
- I already have life insurance.
- I was in my room
getting ready to come down
to the radio station.
I fill in on commercials
and announcements.
- Thank you.
- You don't use the name
Raymond Milburn professionally,
do you?
- No, I use Ray Rock.
- You used to be Ray Mor.
- I get my own
show started soon.
- What's your present schedule?
- Empty.
- I fill in at 10:00 p.m.
cut out at 4:30 a.m.
- That's why I'm
wearing my pajamas.
- How long you lived out here?
- Me?
- Let's see now, I left San
Francisco about 18 months ago.
- Do you have any of
your relative in town?
- Except for the
first couple of weeks,
I lived in a hotel,
got too expensive.
- Anyway.
- Say lieutenant,
there isn't any chance
of keeping this from my parents.
- Mr. and Mrs. Rock?
- Is there?
- Well, we won't notify
them unless it's necessary.
- Why are you so concerned
about keeping this
from your parents?
- Well, they think
I'm at VO Tech
and it'll break their
heart if they knew.
- I have some money coming
to me in a few months,
it was left to me by my uncle
on the condition I don't
get into any difficulties.
- Why do you anticipate
difficulties?
- When I first moved into
the house, I dated Renee,
you know, a few
months, that's all.
That's all it was to it.
- All right, go on.
- Did you kiss her?
- Well, you might as well
know, you'll find out anyway.
- I'm pregnant.
- The only laughs that
girl got came from bottles,
can we put on some Billy's?
Just don't want my
parents to know.
- They're anti deli.
- You know I was talking to
manager a little while ago.
- Seems real nice.
- He told me he got to
work about 25 minutes late
the night the
female was murdered.
- My car cocked out
right on the freeway.
Guy came along, finally gave
me a push, started right off.
- Is that a good enough story?
- Suppose you want
me to prove it?
- That would be nice.
- But I can't,
I have to take his
license number.
- That's it, just back
away nice and slowly.
- That was interrogation
indeed, all right.
- [Narrator]
Intensive questioning
of each suspect
continued for six days.
They re questioned at
their places of business,
at police headquarters
and at the rooming house itself.
Their stories
remained unchanged,
each steadfastly
maintained his innocence
and they gave no outward
appearance of guilt at all.
- Look, you can have the
variety section when he's done.
- All right God
Jackie come on along.
- Invisible army?
I don't see any, now come along.
- So Jesus is my
personal savior.
- Your full name?
- Christopher Mattling,
no middle initial,
let he that committed no
sin cast the first stone.
- We'll cast more
than stones pastor.
Give us straight
answers, no quotes.
- Ever been in jail?
- No.
- Ever been arrested?
- Well, maybe.
- I was picked up
once for vagrancy
but I wasn't booked.
- Get off a cloud seven,
an officious murder committed
and you'll look good.
- Me, why me?
I wouldn't look
twice about that.
- The Charlie Callas defense.
- I knew she was no good the
minute I laid eyes on her,
she was possessed.
- With what?
- Evil, she was evil.
- She brought the birds here.
- I hadn't been there a week
and I knew she would
come to this kind of end.
John 3:8 "He that
committeth sin,
"is of the devil for
the devil sinneth
"from the beginning."
- Knock it off.
- The devil is my
brother-in-law lay off.
- I write right
and give lectures.
- And I wait tables.
- What do you write?
- Stories about the
forces; good and evil,
about God.
- Who buys your talent?
- I had a story in highlights.
- Intellectuals,
I make a living.
- Another brutal
interrogation scene.
- Another senseless
drive-by filming.
- 30 days in the cooler.
That's good water
- So, the water cooler
is conveniently
located at his desk.
- God, I love water, I
think I love it too much.
- Anything?
- Just a few things.
- Nice picture you though.
- Mattling was one of the
first ones on the porch
after Mrs. Coleman called us,
but screwball Mattling even
started to give the girl
her last rites.
- And the crossbow?
- Impossible to trace.
The company that made them
is no longer in business,
they made about
2,500 of the things,
had a fire in their place
and lost their records.
- Do you like meatballs?
- Five men in the house
and only 1.5 million others
in this city to work on.
We can assume for the time
that she knew the person.
She didn't like boyfriends
but for the last
couple of months
she stayed close to the house.
Come in.
- I got here as soon as I could.
I've known Renee since
we were kids together.
It almost killed her mother
when she heard the news.
- Where's he going with this?
- She hasn't been feeling well.
Renee has had a
lot of bad breaks
and I'll admit that
she's been pretty wild.
She's done nothing
to deserve this.
- I'm sure she did.
- That maniac who did
it deserves no trial.
- Take it easy, we're
doing everything we can.
- Now I'd like to ask
Francis the talking mule
a few questions.
- What's got us is the motive.
She had no known
enemies, there's nothing,
there's nothing at
all in the girl's past
to indicate the choose
in serious trouble
of any kind.
- Well, what have
you learned so far?
- Is someone purring?
- And why would you
never see the body?
- A couple of things
we know for sure,
the weapon was a
sporting type crossbow.
- We're checking
renaissance festivals
around the country.
- A window rod was taken
from a hall window,
broken in half
and sharpened with a
file to fit the barrel
and then with its 80 pound pull,
it not only pinned
that girl to the wall.
- It made julienne fries.
- But embedded itself four
inches into a wall stud.
(telephone ringing)
- Speaking of studs,
that's for me.
- What do you got?
- Yes, will you please.
Well, we may have some kind
of a break, I don't know.
In a few minutes, we'll
have a report on the heel.
Now, I'm not raising
too much hope,
it was manufactured
by a large company
and I guess they're.
- Direct from the laundry rooms.
- Literally millions
sold all over the country
and well is about
hundreds of thousands sold
in this area every week.
- It's from the lab.
- She just stole
the whole picture.
- What can I do for you?
- Do you recognize
these pictures?
- Well, that's Bob Crane.
- This looks like the type
of work that Tony turns out.
- Who's Tony?
- He works in the studio
in Hollywood Boulevard.
I think it's right
off a Wilcock,
last names Patini.
- Pardon my spandex.
- These are the
same props he uses,
he does some nice stuff.
Tony can probably
tell you about them.
- I'm going home for lunch.
- Me too.
- Come on, I got some filming.
- Welcome to Winn's.
- Now good girl,
what do you mean we retouch it?
Do I look that I need
excessive retouching?
- But ma'am I tried
to explain to you
when you came in for picture
that we cannot retouch
natural colors.
- I never.
I admit that I have a
few character lives,
but these pictures make
me look years older
that I am.
Why is it the pictures
on display always looks,
when you come to pick up
the finished pictures,
they look just miserable.
- But madam.
- Young lady, my only complaint
is they look just like me.
- That was worth it.
- Where is the owner here?
- Mr. Angeles owns the studio
but he hasn't been here
for about six weeks.
- Since I killed him.
- Him and his wife
are in New York,
however, Mr. Patini
is the manager,
we are the only ones here.
- How long has Mr.
Patini been working here?
- Well, Mr. Patini has
been about four years now.
- Are there any other employees?
- No, we're the only ones here.
- And I don't even work here.
- Could we talk to him please?
- Well, we're pretty
busy right now
but if it's important.
- It's important you.
- You see when you
need our glamor shots
as soon as possible.
- Hey, neat, this day
just keeps getting better.
- Hi, I'm very busy.
- It'll just take a minute.
- Did you take these pictures?
- This one's fuzzy and I'm
blinking in the other one.
- No.
- Look friend, you've
nothing to hide,
just tell the truth.
One of your friends down the
street recognizes your work,
and some of the
props you're using.
- Is this a Docker's ad?
- Fine, thanks for
your times sir.
- We have a few questions
we'd like to ask you downtown.
- All right come on.
- Well, it just doesn't seem
like a quiet little man
who would keep to himself.
- Hey, my gum is
losing its flavor here.
- The bustling city.
- Come back any time.
- Excuse me just gotta
run to the beefy.
- Arnold Stang, fugitive.
- Good luck, meet
you back here Roy.
(upbeat music)
- The loneliness of the
long distance dweeb.
- Come on, can we
just talk about this.
- Stop in the name
of Eddie Deezen.
- Don't hit, I'm
wearing glasses.
I'm sorry I ate
all my band candy.
- Super wedgie.
(upbeat music)
- What's our six-letter
word for toast?
- What's the story on
this guy, Krasker anyway?
- Is he seeing anyone?
- Who, Henry?
That boy's got a good
head on his shoulders.
- Too bad it's not his own.
- I used to work with
his dad years ago
in the crime lab, what a guy.
- My history assignment, sir.
- He asked me to help him with
something he's working on.
- We're putting a
sauna in his basement
- Looks to me like
you're gonna have
that time.
- What the hell does that mean?
- Wow hello let me have
the district attorney's
office please.
Hello Morgan, it's Luis,
what do you mean release Patini?
- Get him, let him.
- He's in a bad mood guy.
- I see your point and thanks.
- Mom said we can't.
- Well, you heard it.
- Actually I didn't sir.
come on let's get out of
here and have a sandwich.
- Benny's not that great
sandwiches around the corner.
- Hey Helmut Kohl's
working the counter.
- Scooch over.
- We had to let him go.
- So help me lieutenant
if you would have let me
handle that man my way
I would have knocked
it out of him.
- It's too bad
but they don't do that anymore.
- Yes, they do.
- If only we could have found
the shoe with a missing heel.
He had every right to
destroy his old shoes.
I've done of myself.
He didn't have to keep.
- It's his constitutional right.
- If we just gone to
that photo studio sooner.
- Regret sir.
- You can't hold a
man or convict him
because he buys a
new pair of shoes.
- That's the basis of
our judicial system.
- Nervousness and the fighting
and the unwillingness to
cooperate and an alibi
he went to a movie.
- Look, I didn't
say he's not guilty,
I just said we can't hold him.
we can't pin a
thing on that guy,
no one can identify him,
we don't have the shoes
to compare the heel with
so we bought a pair of shoes.
It's coincidence.
Buy any good lawyer to
make a monkey out of us
for that kind of a story.
- I still bet lieutenant
if you'd let me try
I'd knock the truth out of him.
- Well don't let it get you.
Benny, check.
- Wait, we never ordered.
- [Narrator] It
was at this point
that our case took
a strange turn.
- All the suspects
moved into my house.
- [Narrator] I was baffled and
had little more to work on.
Dr. Henry Krasker for years
had been working on
an intricate device
to communicate with the dead.
- I do believe the so-called
dead can be contacted,
but only under
certain conditions.
First, all who are concern must
give their full cooperation.
Second and most important.
- Clearance from God.
- No light can be permitted,
except for maybe
a very small one.
- Yes or no, which is it?
- Why is that so important?
- It's rather
difficult to explain,
but remember I know
more than you do.
But a medium has to reach
a certain rate of vibration
to contact anyone
on the other side.
- [Narrator] He was anxious
to try out his theory
and I felt that as long
as I didn't participate in
an official capacity,
it would not involve
the department in
one way or another.
Personally I was
intrigued with the idea
and I'd heard from
before that such a radio
had been worked on by other men.
- I've got lots of food.
- Mr. Thomas Edison
before his death
was interested in
a similar device,
certainly no harm
could come of it.
The plan was to set up
a preliminary meeting
of those involved
and to interest
them in the idea.
If they had nothing to
hide, they wouldn't object.
- In order for them to lower
their vibrations to ours
the go-between or medium must
work in almost total darkness.
And the light should
be suddenly turned on,
they could go into a coma.
- But since they're dead,
it doesn't matter.
- I've known mediums who have
died as a result of the shock.
- Well, live and learn.
- There are other things even
on the perfect conditions
which are not in our favor.
For instance, in this case,
Rene has it on the other
side for just a short while.
- So she's probably
still unpacking.
- So for her to be
able to contact us
she has to go through a
certain learning period.
- Wouldn't it be something
if we could contact her,
would you try?
- Please understand
I'm not a medium.
- I'm a petite.
- But if the rest
of you are willing,
we could give it a try.
- I think it would go
something like this.
- Just take me a
while to prepare.
- I'll have to change
into my tap pants,
they could have taken the
reflector out of the shot
don't you think.
- I gotta order a couple
more drab charcoal suits.
- Hello lieutenant Louis.
- And I'm not very
happy about it.
- You what?
- Calling from a phone
booth, stop that.
- Harry that guy's
crazier than I thought.
- [Narrator] The
first stage was set
and then came the real break,
the one man I wanted
most to observe
during the demonstration
was Patini,
fortunately his curiosity
got the best of him.
Harry was keeping a
close watch on the house
and spotted him looking in the
living room window.
He called me and I relayed
the message to Don Harris
who had expressed an
earlier willingness to help.
- Then I dialed
the phone carefully
after I rechecked the number.
Well, I guess I don't have to
always tell you everything.
- Now, you get in there
and you tell the
manager what you took.
- They can't just
shove them in a house.
- Good, I'll be
right down there.
- I'll just slip into
something more comfortable.
- [Narrator] I arrived at
the house in ten minutes,
we couldn't have asked
for a better setup.
Patini was boiling mad
and I knew something
would happen soon.
- And I was determined to stop.
- You can't keep me here.
I came here to
see all the people
that have caused
me all the trouble,
that's the only reason
I was out there.
- Look I'm not holding you.
As far as I'm concerned you
came here of your own accord.
- But I'm being held
here against my will.
- You will never
keep me in this room.
- Mattling, I'm running
out of patience with you.
- Why am I always subjected to
the work of the devil.
- That's the closet Mattling.
- Are we ready for
a demonstration in
psychic phenomena.
- With no further
obligation on your part.
- I have here a
speaker, a wineglass
and a razor blade.
- Now, the reason for
these unusual objects
is this.
- I hate it when weird guys
have Mary Kate parties.
- If you remember
during World War II,
some of the prisoners of war
made themselves radio receivers
using razor blades and tin foil.
They assembled carefully
and were actually able to
receive radio broadcast.
- Can you stand it?
- Just recently I read of a man
who received the
local radio station
from his medicine chest.
The articles in the
chest were placed
in just the right position
and this enabled him to
hear a music program.
The razor blade is attached
to the speaker by wire
and is then placed
in the wineglass.
- What a relief what
can we do for you guys.
- Hello Nelson say you
know I kind of like
this movie.
I'm intrigued by the
whole interrogation idea
so sit down I want to
ask you a few questions
if you are who you say you are
and I want to know what
you did and what happened.
Don't worry, got all
the time in the world.
- I did it.
- Well I guess that
doesn't really concern me.
- If there is an
entity or spirit
that's huddle in the room
it would be possible for a
method known as telekinesis,
move objects by thought.
The movie vibrator
contain in the speaker.
- I remember something
like that in school.
A student during a
demonstration was
across the table by merely
concentrating on it.
- That's precisely
the same theory
that I hope to
demonstrate here tonight.
Lights please.
Let us all concentrate.
- This is garbage.
- I'm too hip to concentrate
- To be present who
can speak to us.
Can you tell us what
happened on the porch
last Monday night.
Who tell us who?
- They're gonna look
back on this and laugh.
- Who was with us
from the invisible?
Tell us who you are.
It's important that we know.
- To talk to the dead press one,
if you'd like the
Ethereum, the imperium
or the emerald
beyond please hold.
- He's a thick voluptuous man.
- [Narrator] As this was only
an introductory demonstration
to stimulate interest,
I didn't expect it
to happen so fast
but after just a few
minutes in a darkened room.
- I didn't do it, she
was dead when I got here.
I was doing was loving
her pictures I swear it.
She was dead against the
wall when I got here.
- Shalt communicate
with it is the wisdom
of Solomon in the
book of Proverbs
in the house of the
righteous is much straighter
but in the revenues
of the wickedest.
- After Mattling
my sudden outbreak
it was impossible
to continue further.
- I want the whole
story Patini, now.
- It's the truth, I swear it.
I'll sign a statement, anything.
When I got here about 9:30
I found her.
I was bringing
pictures she wanted,
she told me she had to
have him before morning
to show it to an agency.
I pushed the door
open, she wasn't there.
- I put her
underwear on my head.
- I laid the pictures
on top of the dresser.
I came back down the hall
and started for the porch steps
and then I saw this things
sticking out of her neck.
Just then a woman
step out of the house
and I knew I was it if I
didn't get out of there,
so I started running.
I must have caught my
here on the porch dip,
it ripped off.
- We could use a flashback.
Remember, this is
a motion picture.
- You could have saved
us a lot of trouble
if you'd told us that
in the first place.
- If there are no objections
I like, let's call them meeting.
Tomorrow night at my laboratory,
they'll be no interruptions
there, nine o'clock.
- [Narrator] I was inclined
to believe Patini's story,
he offered no objection
to attending a second
demonstration the
following night.
No one of the group objected
and I began to wonder if we
were on the wrong track again.
Krasker's lab was
a makeshift affair
in the basement of
a store building
a few blocks from
the rooming house.
- Last night after
the demo,nstration,
I came back here to the lab.
I noticed some small objects
floating around the room.
I realized that someone
on the other side
was trying to contact me,
but it wasn't until
a few hours ago
that I found out it was Rene.
It's my theory that
when a person expires
a certain glow
radiates from the body.
Something like a tube
that has turned off.
This radiation test cannot
see seen by most people
is called fox glow.
Fox glow is a
minute radio signal,
that can be amplified
powerful enough
to activate certain minerals
such as this prepared crystal.
The signal is then filtered
through standard radio equipment
and by this method we
can communicate directly
with the deceased.
- Didn't you cover this
in yesterday's lectures.
- When I realized that Rene
was trying to send a message
I worked with the
frequencies and adjusted
the variable vibration pitch
until I found just
the right combination.
- But I was still getting
that annoying hum.
- It's Renee.
- Let's see, I'll turn on
some unrelated electrical
equipment to make it pretty.
- I'd like to thank
Edmond Scientific,
for their generous
support of this project.
(upbeat music)
- I don't have roadies, so I'll.
- Seeing even licorice whip
attached to this gizmo.
- Let's see, I'll
patch 345 to complement
it's symmetric.
- That'll be in a
minute, don't worry.
- Hey, Krasker you're one
there is kind of floating.
- Hold it, that's not
supposed to happen.
That belongs to me, thank you.
- Maybe you guys should
break into small groups
at this point.
- His curling iron.
- Sorry folks went a lot
better in rehearsal
it'll be just a moment.
- An anxious Bob Dill.
- [Narrator] We
were all surprised
when the Rosetta iron beeped.
- Hello.
- They hung up.
- I'm speaking to anyone
on the 18 MOC range.
- [Narrator] Incredible?
- Not really.
- [Narrator] Unbelievable?
- No.
- [Narrator] Thousands
of unexplainable sounds
have been heard on frequencies
of varying lengths,
only a few of them
were ever traced down.
They were usually
explained off as static
of one sort or another.
Henry Krasker was
a credible man,
brilliant and rational,
and I also knew he was
something of a showman.
- This was clearly an off night.
- [Narrator] But
about his radio device
he was sincere.
Just how far he had progressed
toward his completion,
I was not aware.
Krasker's effects were
certainly succeeding
in making those present nervous.
- Sam, I said no witchcraft.
- Why, thank you the dead.
- The dead is so powerful.
- So, big deal my stools float.
- Do you see what I mean?
- Don't the dead just bug you,
come on back me up.
- Look at the pounds
of sweat in this shot.
- Can you hear me clearly?
- Otherwise, I could
hang up and call back.
- I'm trying to be dead
could you keep it down.
- Not very clear.
- What, do you talk to the dead?
- Not so loud, I
think I hear a voice.
- Who Renee, who?
- The dead, could you turn
your radio down please.
- Say that again.
- It was kind of funny.
- Who Renee, who?
- I can't remember
who killed me,
it hardly matters.
- Repeat that.
(siren wailing)
- Renee must love Jesus.
- Now he's supposed to bring
her Diet Coke or something?
- I'm having a reaction.
- So there's Bonnie
Lake, what do you know.
- Canada, the land.
- So you're not dead.
- Never said I was.
- I knew this was a trick.
You didn't fall down and
I couldn't have hit you,
when they wouldn't
show us the body,
I knew you weren't dead.
- What I mean was it was so
obvious I didn't kill you.
- You married the girl
two months ago in Tijuana.
We found the wreckage
this afternoon,
now tell me the rest.
- Two months ago.
It all started two months ago.
- Did it start two months ago?
- We were out on a wild tear
and I got all tanked up.
- Looks like two
months ago I think.
- She talked me into
getting married.
If my parents would
have found out,
they would have cut
me off without a cent.
It wasn't so bad at first,
all she wanted was
small amounts of money.
And she demanded more and more.
She threatened to tell my dad.
- Now I understand.
- Where did you
get the crossbow?
- Well, Metro Archery in Blaine.
- I had it in my room.
I got it from my father
years ago in San Francisco.
- His grandmother
knitted it for him,
he told me to shoot
conniving blondes with it.
- We used to hunt together.
- He'd hunt me and
then I'd hunt him,
it was a good system.
- That night she said she
wanted a lot of money.
- He is so not
from San Francisco.
- I had no way in the
world of getting it
unless I told my folks,
then came the pay off.
- Are you there God?
It's me Margaret.
She said she was
going to have a baby.
If that was true I know it
couldn't have been mine.
- I took some shrapnel down.
- I knew she was chasing around
and I didn't care.
- The effect of jazz on youth.
- I don't know what
happened to me.
After she left my room.
- I started sharpening
a curtain rod
and everything just snowballed.
- Narrow out of a window rod,
and I sharpened it.
- I disguise myself
as a bison calf.
- Well, look just
don't do it again.
- [Narrator] It was I that
insisted on substituting Hope
instead of Renee's body.
- I have to take
credit for that.
- You know Henry your
methods are a bit fency,
but also very effective.
- [Narrator] But in all
fairness to Dr. Henry Krasker
and to others were
earnestly striving
to perfect just such a radio.
Henry to this day insists
that his long worked on radio
would have been successful
if he had been given
opportunity to try it.
Would he actually
have been able to?
- What are you doing?
- Will men ever
be able to contact
the other side with a machine?
Will the dead talk back?
- The meetings adjourned.
Harry, you can come down now.
- Yes, another great
Saul Bass title sequence.
They were in it fine
great, who cares.
- And of course the
dead as themselves.
- I just realized they
never talked to the dead.
- Never got round to that.
- Captain Trips, you wanna
give it a rest there.
- Almost done Mikey.
- Well done or not, I'm
gonna read a letter.
Put this up on stills.
This one is from Matt Klein.
- When Matt Klein sat
down to write his letter
to the satellite of love,
little did he know he had
only 17 minutes to live.
- That's not true.
Matt Klein writes,
MST3K is the best thing
to happen to television
since Nell Carter exploded.
- Yes, Nell Carter had exploded
but many metaphysicists believe
she can still order up
for Subway sandwiches
from beyond the grave.
- Your wit and humor
is so outstanding
even Conrad Bain takes
a backseat to all.
- Yes, even though Conrad Bain
has yet to pass from this world,
the most skilled
occultists cannot prove
he still walks the earth.
(siren wailing)
(all muttering)
- Well, fun is where
you find it Brian.
Now, hold it still Frank.
- [Frank] Here, Dr. Forrester.
- Now cut it out you scam.
- [Frank] How about if
I hold it over here?
- That's it, that's good.
- [Frank] Missed again,
not a scratch on it.
- Well until the 12th of
never you big diaper heads.
(both laughing)
(funky guitar music)